Muhammad Chandra Buwana

Email : cbuwana@gmail.com Phone : 085225623599

LinkedIn : https://www.linkedin.com/in/muhammad-chandra-buwana-279334128/

Github : https://github.com/chandrabuwana

EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

I am a well-planned person and like about new technology. I am graduate from Pembangunan Nasional 'Veteran' Yogyakarta University majoring Informatic Engineering. 5 Years Experienced Software Engineer specializing in React and React Native Development for Hybrid Apps and Web Apps in the Tech Industry

FUNCTIONAL EXPERTISE

- Node.js & Express (Intermediate)
- HTML CSS (Intermediate)
- Vuex (Intermediate)
- Arduino
- React Native
- Git
- MongoDb

- InfluxDb
- PostgresQL
- Grafana
- React JS
- Vue JS
- Next JS
- Typescript

RELEVANT PROJECTS

Motorcycle Key use ID Card for Start Engine and System Security

Role : back-end engineer, collaborated with other 4 team members

Language : C# & Arduino

Project description:

Devices that was built with Arduino and C#. That devices has been applied to motorcycle and works.

Drink Reminder (DriMer)

A health tracker application for detect activity of user and suggest liquid needs base on user activity.

Role : BackEnd engineer, collaborated with other 4 team members

Language : Javascript

Framework and Libraries : React Native, React Native Sensor, React Native Audio (FrontEnd)

NodeJs, Express, Mongodb (BackEnd)

Source Code : https://github.com/AhmadNizar/DrimerServer.v2 (Backend)

https://github.com/AhmadNizar/DriMerClient.v1 (FrontEnd)

HacktivOverflow

A question and answer forum

Role : Solo Project **Language** : Javascript

Frameworks and Libraries : NodeJs, ExpressJs, Mongoose, Vue & Vuex, Google Cloud Platform

Project description: A question and answer that user can post a question, answer and up/down

vote question and answer

Source Code : https://github.com/chandrabuwana/hacktivoverflow

EfundingApps

Application for peer to peer lending basic with crowdfunding.

Role :Full Stack Developer

Language : Javascript

Frameworks and Libraries : React-Native, NodeJs, ExpressJs, Mongoose, Vultr

Project Description : Efunding Apps is Platform Mobile Apps for lender who already have

campaign and want to be funded by borrower.

Asmin Admin Website

Application for employees give rating and comment to another employees.

Role : React Developer

Language : Javascript
Frameworks and Libraries : ReactJS

Project Description : Asmin admin website is website for admin to register new employee

and see chart for 1 years.

Msight Data Visualisation

Visualizing data insight from MSight Database

Role : Data Visualisation Analyst

Language : Bash Frameworks and Libraries : -

Project Description : Msight data visualisation is project from msight to see behavior of user

from user Msight and to give sugesstion to another company.

BKPP Portal

Application for government employees at BKPP Bontang

Role : Frontend Dev
Language : Javascript
Frameworks and Libraries : React-native.js

Project Description: BKPP portal is mobile application android for government employees

see status and personal data.

Website Telkomsel

Website Telkomsel data analytic

Role : Frontend Dev Language : Javascript

Frameworks and Libraries : ReactJs, Google Tag Manager

Project Description: Website Telkomsel data analytic is useful for informing MSight Department to see behavior or user that use website telkomsel from promo, feature and etc.

Junkfood Mobile App

Delivery order food mobile application Role : Frontend Dev Language : Javascript

Frameworks and Libraries : React-NativeJs

Project Description :Junkfood App is Beta Project from Telkomsel for delivery food. There

are 3 app User App, Merchant App, and Taker App.

FITCO Mobile App

Online booking application

Role : Frontend Dev
Language : Javascript
Frameworks and Libraries : React-NativeJs

Project Description :Fitco App is platform from The Fit Company for online booking

Gym, Coach, Class and to buy some groceries and fitness equipment.

Values Daily Assessment (VDA) Mobile App

Online booking application

Role : Frontend Dev
Language : Javascript
Frameworks and Libraries : React-Native.Js

Project Description :VDA App is platform employee performance app for assessing fellow

employees 360 degree that uses by 3000 employees under PT Turangga Resources

Ternak Uang Mobile App

Platform for financial literacy

Role : Frontend Dev
Language : Javascript
Frameworks and Libraries : React-Native.Js

Project Description :Ternak Uang is a comprehensive investment and financial education

app that aims to empower individuals to achieve financial freedom. It provides a wealth of

knowledge and resources to help users learn about various investment strategies, manage their finances effectively, and make informed financial decisions. With over 300,000 users, Ternak Uang

has established itself as a leading platform for financial literacy in Indonesia.

Bisa Trade Web App

Online booking application

Role : Frontend Dev Language : Javascript

Frameworks and Libraries : Next.Js, Tailwind

Project Description : Bisa trade is a portal to bring together exporters from Indonesia with importers from abroad, here importers can see data and information from Indonesian exporters starting from the goods supplied, the price of goods to the address of the exporter itself.

Bisa Ekspor Web

Landing page

Role : Frontend Dev
Language : Javascript
Frameworks and Libraries : Next.Js, Tailwind

Project Description : Bisa Ekspor is an Indonesian digital platform that aims to empower individuals and businesses to participate in the global export market. It provides a comprehensive ecosystem of services and resources to assist aspiring exporters in navigating the complex processes of international trade.

EDUCATION

Bootcamp (Full-Stack Web Development). Hacktiv8 (Jakarta, Indonesia)

(Informatic Engineering).

(UPNVYK) Pembangunan Nasional 'Veteran' Yogyakarta University (Yogyakarta, Indonesia)

SMAN 01 Singosari (Malang, Indonesia)

2010

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

BEM Fakultas Teknologi Industri

2015 - 2016

BEM is a organization for college student that has a mission to associate 3 Majors from 1 Faculty. I have been a part of BEM Fakultas Teknologi Industri at Human, Press and Propaganda. There are many events that had been held for College Student at Technology Faculty. These were my following activities:

- Communicating about event-event like discussion, seminar that happen at faculty
- Publishing about new technology that has correlation in 3 majors; there are many sides that we publicy to our college student

Multimedia Community

2014 - 2015

Multimedia Community is a community for students who enjoy Photography, Videography, and Design at Informatic Engineering major. In this community, they will be prepared for a contest. This community focuses

in 3 division. These were what I have done:

- Photography Contest at my University
- Make Photo shoot for major event
- Photo Show at the final of batch community

Jogja Vario Community

2011 - 2016

I like traveling and meeting new people, so I decided to join Jogja Vario Community. I have joined this community around 5 years and managed to make friends from anywhere especially from Papua and Sumatera. In this community, we were sharing about motor modification events, social events and many more.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

PT. Indonesia Bisa Ekspor

December 2022 - Present

I have worked in Indonesia Bisa Ekspor, a company focuse on Education for export business. I have built and maintenance Bisa trade web app is focusing as a place to meet overseas importers who want to meet exporters from Indonesia directly. By knowing where the manufacturer is and other confidential information, Bisa ekspor web app ,Bisa trade web app, CMS Bisa Trade, and CMS Bisa Ekspor using Next.JS Frontend Framework and use Antd, Tailwind as UI Framework

PT. Karya Hasta Dinamika

January 2021 - December 2022

I have worked in Karya Hasta Dinamika, a company member of Kalbe Group aims to improve the quality of people's lives through health and wellness. It offers medical information, connects user with doctor, and provides health tips, articles, and consultation services via mobile App and Web App. I have built and maintenance Kalcare Web App, KlikDokter Web App, KlikDokter Back Office using Next.JS Frontend FrameWork and use Antd as Ui Framework

PT. Trifecta Fit Tangguh

October 2019 - November 2020

I have worked in Trifecta Fit Tangguh, a company member of FITCO (FIT Company) aims to improve the quality of people's lives through health and wellness. To achieve this, we combine tech innovation in integrating wellness services into an easily accessible platform by people to enjoy an active and healthy lifestyle. I have built Apps Fitco for IOS and Android with React Native and Dashboard/CMS with React Js, Node Js.

PT. Phincon

September 2018 - October 2019

I have worked in Phincon (Phintraco Consulting), a company member of Phintraco Group, is an Information Technology (IT) consulting and services company. Established in 2008, we are focusing on providing

customers with all spectrums of Customer Relationship Management (CRM) solutions and Middleware solutions.

PT. Efunding Teknologi Keuangan

February 2018-August 2018

I have worked in Financial Technology for 7 months. I built server and make Mobile Apps interface for EfundingApp and server for Wakapp Website. This company is involved in Financial Technology Syaria. I built with Node.Js and MongoDb for Database.

Dinas Pertanian Yogyakarta System Information Division

Januari 2015 - Maret 2015

I was an intern at this division with my partner. In this office, I built website for a library. The office does not have a good archive management. If we look for some report, sometimes we can't find it and some workers are confused with that problems so we decided to build Library website to manage manage books, reports and many more.